# KAROL SHIRLEY

## SUMMARY

I am a versatile software developer with 7+ years in Java-based backend applications, DevOps, frontend websites, and video game development. Able to work independently and complete features from inception to production, I have a high focus on quality using test driven development and continuous integration to build robust software systems. I am seeking a remote role in the US that is focused on server development and DevOps.

#### SKILLS

- **Backend:** Java, Kotlin, C# (.NET), REST, gRPC, Spring, Dropwizard, GraphQL, Protocol Buffers, Axon Framework, Akka, Liquibase, Flyway, Redis, Elasticache, JUnit/Mockito, Dagger, Maven, Gradle, RxJava
- Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, NoSQL, MSSQL
- Infrastructure: AWS, Google Cloud, Kubernetes, Docker, Terraform, CloudFormation
- Frontend: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Hugo, WordPress, Unity3D, UniRx, Zenject
- Tools: Git, JIRA, Datadog, Swagger (Open API)

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan 2022 - July 2022

Step - Palo Alto, California, USA (Remote)

- Implemented core platform features for US fintech start-up, including cashback rewards, push notifications, and risk assessment using Kotlin, gRPC, Dagger, Protocol Buffers, PostgreSQL and Gradle
- Participated in on-call rotation, monitoring services in Google Cloud, investigating and responding to incidents

#### SENIOR JAVA DEVELOPER

Feb 2020 - Dec 2021

HyperJar - London, United Kingdom (On-site & Remote)

- Developed core platform features for UK fintech start-up such as open banking, scheduled transactions, consumer analytics, awards, and video KYC using Java, Spring, MySQL, and Axon Framework
- Maintained cloud infrastructure in AWS (ECS, EKS, RDS, CloudWatch, Route53, S3, CloudFormation and IAM)
- Collaborated with product, engineering and CX on new features and bug fixes using agile methodologies

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Sep 2018 - Jan 2020

Expeflow - Waterloo, ON, Canada

- Worked in small company of 8 to develop features full stack for Expeflow's cloud-based workflow automation system using Java, PostgreSQL, Flyway, JSP, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, Less, and jQuery
- Coordinated with clients, and team to define scope and deliverables for feature requests

## CO-FOUNDER, PRESIDENT & CEO

Sep 2016 - Sep 2018

56 Game Studios - Waterloo, ON, Canada

- Founded video game start-up with two others, managing and working in all business departments
- Developed features full stack for PC game System Siege using Java, Dropwizard, NoSQL, and Unity3D/C#
- Established and maintained cloud infrastructure in AWS (ECS, CodeDeploy, DynamoDB, Route53, S3, IAM) and CI/CD pipeline using Terraform and Bitbucket Pipelines
- Designed and developed company websites using HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript, Hugo, Bootstrap, and Photoshop
- Successfully pitched and awarded \$60,000 In seed capital from AC JumpStart University of Waterloo

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Electronic Arts - Kitchener, ON, Canada

- Designed, implemented, and tested features for real-time chat service built in Java using Akka, Redis, and RxJava, hosted in AWS for mobile titles such as Plants vs. Zombies Heroes
- Improved cloud infrastructure to help reduce costs and increase security, updated tooling, and migrated services

## PAID INTERNSHIPS/CO-OPS

- Completed seven 4 month paid internships/co-ops from May 2009 to September 2014 (2+ years total)
- Worked in QA, front-end web, backend (ASP.NET and Java), and game development (Unity3D/C#) at Christie Digital, BMO Bank, BlackBerry, and EA

# **EDUCATION**

University of Waterloo Sep. 2008 – Apr. 2015 Bachelor of Computer Science Co-op with Software Engineering Option